<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lightning on 21ideas</title>
    <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lightning on 21ideas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Lightning Network?</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/what-is-lightning-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/what-is-lightning-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why should you care about Lightning Network, how does it work and how to use it? We&amp;rsquo;ll answer these and many other questions in this guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint btc&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;The article written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://snort.social/p/npub10awzknjg5r5lajnr53438ndcyjylgqsrnrtq5grs495v42qc6awsj45ys7&#34;&gt;Tony⚡️&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.223:1313/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Network is a decentralized system for instant micro payments. Bitcoin, the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used and valued cryptocurrency, allows anyone to transfer value without the need for a trusted third party. Bitcoin supports an advanced scripting system that allows users to program instructions for managing their funds. However, Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s design has a number of drawbacks. It can take an hour, and often more, from the time a transaction is made on the Bitcoin blockchain to the moment that transaction gets finalized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Wallets</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning-wallets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With repeated bumps of the popularity of monkey JPEGs on the Bitcoin blockchain and in anticipation of the upcoming bull market, onchain fees are a thing to consider in the upcoming future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;imageWrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://192.168.1.223:1313/img/ln-wallets/high-fees.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fees in the network can reach hundreds of sats per virtual byte, and this is far from the limit. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mempool.space/&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Network provides a solution to the painful problem of high fees, but you need to act thoughtfully, without rushing. That&amp;rsquo;s why today I suggest to analyze the best available Lightning wallets and evaluate the pros and cons of each wallet, so that you can choose the best solution and finally forget about high fees (or at least minimize the stress).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Lightning Address Works</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/how-lightning-address-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/how-lightning-address-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More experienced users know, that nowadays you can send satoshis directly to Lightning Address in user@domain format. But how exactly does this work?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this short article I would like to explain it to those who do not know it. At the same time, I will describe the basics of Lightning invoices and LNURL-pay protocol.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint btc&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;This article by @heisenberg was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://stacker.news/items/65872&#34;&gt;stacker.news&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.223:1313/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lightning-invoices-basics&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Lightning invoices basics&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#lightning-invoices-basics&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lightning Invoices are nowadays the standard for sending and receiving funds on the Lightning Network. If you want to receive some satoshis, you have to generate an invoice on your node/wallet. An invoice is nothing more than a text string (which starts with lnbc&amp;hellip;) and contains, among other things, the recipient ID and the amount. There is actually more information but we won&amp;rsquo;t go into that now. The invoice is most often shared using a QR code, which is nothing more than an image representation of the string described earlier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Network Privacy</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning-network-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning-network-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint btc&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;This article by Tony was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://abytesjourney.com/lightning-privacy&#34;&gt;abytesjourney.com&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.223:1313/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Lightning Network has been growing recently, with around &lt;a href=&#34;https://1ml.com/statistics&#34;&gt;11,000 active public nodes out of around 20,000 total&lt;/a&gt;. Besides the advantage of near-instant payments, there can be privacy improvements to Lightning as well. Unfortunately, there are scenarios where Lightning is not great for privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’d like to unearth some of these. Not as FUD about the network, but to keep people as informed as possible so they may privately use Lightning. Everything in this article is public knowledge and known to the industry to some degree. This is my attempt at aggregating the topic of Lightning privacy from a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Lightning centralized?</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/is-lightning-centralized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/is-lightning-centralized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hold your horses, Darth will explain you how to &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; those charts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint btc&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;This article by DarthCoin was published in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://darthcoin.substack.com/p/omg-ln-nodes-are-running-on-amazon&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.223:1313/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OK plebs, by another request from my readers, they asked me to interpret / read this chart, being scared that the chart is showing that many LN nodes are “running” on Amazon, Google etc and LN is “cEnTrAlIzEd”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think originally this FUD was launched on internet by the XRP/ETH guys, trying to diminish the normies “trust” in Bitcoin and create panic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Network Explained</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning-network-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/lightning-network-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint btc&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;This article by Dmitry Laptev was published in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/lightningto-me/lightning-network-45b4b2119d97&#34;&gt;Medium blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.223:1313/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, we discuss why we need it (part 0) and describe an idea of payment channels and Lightning Network (part 1). Then we introduce required building blocks (part 2) and see how these blocks can be used to create payment channels (part 3). We then finally build Lightning Network, discuss its properties (part 4), and sum it all up (part 5).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solutions to inbound liquidity problem</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/inbound-liquidity-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://192.168.1.223:1313/en/inbound-liquidity-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint btc&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;This article by Dmitry Laptev was published in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/lightningto-me/practical-solutions-to-inbound-capacity-problem-in-lightning-network-60224aa13393&#34;&gt;Medium blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.223:1313/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to accept payments through lightning network or to properly balance your channels — your node needs to have sufficient &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;inbound capacity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This article describes what that is and practical ways to get it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Update(July 2021): three years after it was written, this post is still mostly accurate, but some ways of getting inbound liquidity are missing or outdated. The services I mostly recommend nowadays are: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lightning.engineering/loop/&#34;&gt;lightning loop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lightning.engineering/pool/&#34;&gt;lightning pool&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnbig.com/#/&#34;&gt;lnbig.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lightningnetwork.plus/&#34;&gt;lightningnetwork.plus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/theRingsOfFire&#34;&gt;t.me/theRingsOfFire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ln2me.com/&#34;&gt;ln2me.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
