<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lightning on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning/</link><description>Recent content in Lightning on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/lightning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Что такое Лайтнинг?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/chto-takoe-laitning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/chto-takoe-laitning/</guid><description>Зачем нужна сеть Лайтнинг, как она работает и как ей пользоваться?
Статья подготовлена Тони⚡️. Поддержать проект. Сеть лайтнинг (Lightning Network) является децентрализованной системой для мгновенных микроплатежей. Биткоин, самая широко используемая и ценная в мире криптовалюта, позволяет любому передать ценность без необходимости в доверенном посреднике или депозитарии. Биткоин поддерживает продвинутую систему скриптов (сценариев), позволяющую пользователям программировать инструкции по распоряжению собственными средствами. Тем не менее, дизайн Биткоина обладает рядом недостатков. С момента совершения сделки на блокчейне Биткоина и до момента, когда эта сделка станет необратимой, может пройти час, а часто и больше.</description></item><item><title>Лайтнинг-кошельки</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-wallets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-wallets/</guid><description>С повторяющимися всплесками популярности картинок обезьян в блокчейне Биткоина и в преддверии предстоящего бычьего рынка комиссии в основной сети не особо радуют.
Комиссии в сети могут достигать сотен сат за виртуальный байт, и это далеко не предел. Источник
Лайтнинг предоставляет решение наболевшей проблемы высоких комиссий, но действовать нужно продуманно, не торопясь. Поэтому сегодня предлагаю разобрать лучшие доступные лайтнинг-кошельки, оценить плюсы и минусы каждого из них, чтобы вы могли выбрать лучшее решение и наконец забыть (или хотя бы минимизировать стресс) о высоких комиссиях.</description></item><item><title>How Lightning Address Works</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/how-lightning-address-works/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/how-lightning-address-works/</guid><description>More experienced users know, that nowadays you can send satoshis directly to Lightning Address in user@domain format. But how exactly does this work?
In this short article I would like to explain it to those who do not know it. At the same time, I will describe the basics of Lightning invoices and LNURL-pay protocol.
This article by @heisenberg was published on stacker.news website.
Contribute.
Lightning invoices basics # Lightning Invoices are nowadays the standard for sending and receiving funds on the Lightning Network.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Privacy</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-network-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-network-privacy/</guid><description>This article by Tony was published on abytesjourney.com website.
Contribute.
The Lightning Network has been growing recently, with around 11,000 active public nodes out of around 20,000 total. Besides the advantage of near-instant payments, there can be privacy improvements to Lightning as well. Unfortunately, there are scenarios where Lightning is not great for privacy.
I’d like to unearth some of these. Not as FUD about the network, but to keep people as informed as possible so they may privately use Lightning.</description></item><item><title>Is Lightning centralized?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/is-lightning-centralized/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/is-lightning-centralized/</guid><description>Hold your horses, Darth will explain you how to &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; those charts.
This article by DarthCoin was published in his blog.
Contribute.
OK plebs, by another request from my readers, they asked me to interpret / read this chart, being scared that the chart is showing that many LN nodes are “running” on Amazon, Google etc and LN is “cEnTrAlIzEd”.
I think originally this FUD was launched on internet by the XRP/ETH guys, trying to diminish the normies “trust” in Bitcoin and create panic.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Explained</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-network-explained/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-network-explained/</guid><description>This article by Dmitry Laptev was published in his Medium blog.
Contribute.
First, we discuss why we need it (part 0) and describe an idea of payment channels and Lightning Network (part 1). Then we introduce required building blocks (part 2) and see how these blocks can be used to create payment channels (part 3). We then finally build Lightning Network, discuss its properties (part 4), and sum it all up (part 5).</description></item><item><title>Solutions to inbound liquidity problem</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/inbound-liquidity-problem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/inbound-liquidity-problem/</guid><description>This article by Dmitry Laptev was published in his Medium blog.
Contribute.
If you want to accept payments through lightning network or to properly balance your channels — your node needs to have sufficient inbound capacity. This article describes what that is and practical ways to get it.
Update(July 2021): three years after it was written, this post is still mostly accurate, but some ways of getting inbound liquidity are missing or outdated.</description></item></channel></rss>