<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Privacy on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in Privacy on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Privacy: Best Practices</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/best-practices/</guid><description>There is a sacred realm of privacy where essential rights and liberties into which the law, generally speaking, must not intrude.
This article by Gigi was published on swanbitcoin.com website.
Contribute.
“There is a sacred realm of privacy for every man and woman where he makes his choices and decisions — a realm of his own essen­tial rights and liber­ties into which the law, gener­ally speaking, must not intrude.”
— Geoffrey Fisher, Archbishop of Canter­bury (1959)</description></item><item><title>no-KYC only. Avoid the creep</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/no-kyc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/no-kyc/</guid><description>This article by Bitcoin Q+A was published on bitcoinqna.github.io website.
Contribute.
What is KYC? # KYC or ‘Know your customer’ is a regulation that any businesses with a banking relationship has to abide by. Bitcoin exchanges are no different. These rules are imposed worldwide and are geared towards ensuring that a business acting as a money exchange and/or transmitter has ‘suitable’ information on every customer they serve.
Within the Bitcoin space, ‘creeping KYC’ is a disease that is slowly spreading.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Privacy</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/wiki-bitcoin-privacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/wiki-bitcoin-privacy/</guid><description>While Bitcoin can support strong privacy, many ways of using it are usually not very private. With a proper understanding of the technology, bitcoin can indeed be used in a very private and anonymous way.
This article was published on en.bitcoin.it wiki.
Contribute.
As of 2019 most casual enthusiasts of bitcoin believe it is perfectly traceable; this is completely false. Around 2011 most casual enthusiasts believed it is totally private; which is also false.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Becomes Critical</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-becomes-critical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-becomes-critical/</guid><description>An EU draft resolution calling for a “balance” between encryption and surveillance once again underscored the need for technologies like Bitcoin.
This article by Peter Chawaga was published on Bitcoin Magazine website.
Contribute.
On November 6, 2020, the Council of the European Union released a “Draft Council Resolution on Encryption.” The document is supposed to serve as a precursor to a final text to be presented to the Council, on November 19 for potential legal adoption.</description></item><item><title>BIP47, the ugly duckling</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bip47-the-ugly-duckling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bip47-the-ugly-duckling/</guid><description>This English translation of an article by Loïc Morel was published on sovrnbitcoiner.com website.
Contribute.
&amp;ldquo;He is too great,&amp;rdquo; they all said, and the rooster of India, who had come into the world with spurs and believed himself to be emperor, inflated himself like a building all sails out, and walked straight on him in great fury and red to the eyes. The poor duck did not know whether to stop or walk: he was saddened to be scorned by all the ducks of the court.</description></item><item><title>CoinJoin Overview</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/coinjoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/privacy/coinjoin/</guid><description>This article by @BitcoinOnly_ and @6102bitcoin was published on 6102bitcoin.com website.
Contribute.
Background # Bitcoin transactions are public by nature; they map inputs (unspent utxo’s) to outputs (new unspent utxo’s) in a way that is auditable by anyone with access to the bitcoin blockchain (the history of transactions). Yet interpreting these transactions and the Blockchain is a non-trivial task, because Bitcoin transaction are not equivalent to Bitcoin payments.
The Problem # Because anyone can see the links between transaction inputs and outputs it’s possible for anyone to analyse previous and future transaction behavior in an attempt to link multiple Bitcoin addresses to the same entity, this process is sometimes called clustering.</description></item></channel></rss>