<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Bitcoin, Not Shitcoin</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/not-shitcoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/not-shitcoin/</guid><description>Why bitcoin is not only the best investment of our time, and the only good “crypto,” but the only moral, economic and philosophically sound place to store your wealth.
This article by Aleksandar Svetski was published in Bitcoin Magazine.
Contribute.
Hint: Beyond Bitcoin, it’s ALL shitcoin.
I often get asked about “which crypto” is a good one to invest in. Of course, my answer is always bitcoin. Period.
In this article I’d like to lay out the rationale from three angles:</description></item><item><title>Inalienable Property Rights</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/inalienable-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/inalienable-property-rights/</guid><description>This essay by Gigi was published on dergigi.com website.
Contribute.
Video bitcoinized by RD ₿TC, based on an edit by Ampleforth.
Original source: An interview with F.A. Hayek (1984)
Law. Language. Money. The three paradigms of spontaneous and emergent order in society. Moral questions are at the root of it all:
Who should be allowed to speak? Who should be allowed to publish? Who should be allowed to have property?</description></item><item><title>The Crypto Anarchist Manifesto</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-anarchist-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-anarchist-manifesto/</guid><description>From: tcmay@netcom.com (Timothy C. May)
Subject: The Crypto Anarchist Manifesto
Date: Sun, 22 Nov 92 12:11:24 PST
Cypherpunks of the World,
Several of you at the &amp;ldquo;physical Cypherpunks&amp;rdquo; gathering yesterday in Silicon Valley requested that more of the material passed out in meetings be available electronically to the entire readership of the Cypherpunks list, spooks, eavesdroppers, and all. &amp;lt;Gulp&amp;gt;
Here&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;Crypto Anarchist Manifesto&amp;rdquo; I read at the September 1992 founding meeting.</description></item><item><title>A Cypherpunk's Manifesto</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/cypherpunks-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/cypherpunks-manifesto/</guid><description>by Eric Hughes
Privacy is necessary for an open society in the electronic age. Privacy is not secrecy. A private matter is something one doesn&amp;rsquo;t want the whole world to know, but a secret matter is something one doesn&amp;rsquo;t want anybody to know. Privacy is the power to selectively reveal oneself to the world.
If two parties have some sort of dealings, then each has a memory of their interaction. Each party can speak about their own memory of this; how could anyone prevent it?</description></item><item><title>Is Bitcoin Like the Dutch Tulip Bubble?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/dutch-tulip-bubble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/dutch-tulip-bubble/</guid><description>This article by Yan Pritzker was published on swanbitcoin.com website.
Contribute.
If you could use tulips to instantly transmit value across the globe to anyone in any country, regard­less of whether they had a functioning govern­ment or banking system.
If the govern­ment couldn’t come to your door and take away your tulips or control who you could sell them to or in what ways.
If tulips could last for hundreds of years or millennia and be handed down to your children, redeemed for other forms of value.</description></item><item><title>Everyone's a Scammer</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/everyones-a-scammer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/everyones-a-scammer/</guid><description>This article by Michael Goldstein was published on the Satoshi Nakamoto Institute website.
Contribute.
Suggested background reading music There&amp;rsquo;s a War Going On # Bonnie and Clyde cannot simply rob First National Block Chain. They can hack servers and unencrypted wallet files or scan low-entropy brain wallets. But the costs of obtaining bitcoins hoarded on a high-entropy, password-protected paper wallet, for instance, are incredibly high. A computer cannot be expected to brute force the wallet in the universe’s lifetime, so a trespasser would have to employ expensive tactics such as kidnapping and torture on any prospective, individual target.</description></item><item><title>The Freedom of Value</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/freedom-of-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/freedom-of-value/</guid><description>This article by Gigi was published on dergigi.com website.
Contribute.
How Value-for-Value Fixes the Monetization of Information # The internet has a problem. Few people know that this problem exists, but hey, that&amp;rsquo;s the nature of serious, non-obvious problems: they are invisible until they aren&amp;rsquo;t. The problem with the internet is that information wants to be free. And if something wants to be free as in freedom, given enough time, it will also be free as in beer.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Is The Only Real Meme</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-meme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-meme/</guid><description>This thread by Gigi was published in his Twitter.
Contribute.
“This is our meme world, everyone else is just living in it.” With this quote by @bitstein I began my talk about “memes” and “the world” at the @BTCZitadelle this weekend.
My talk wasn’t about memes, since I wouldn’t be able to top Bitstein’s talk anyway.
It was about the difference between memes and the world.
Memes are thoughts, ideas, information.</description></item><item><title>The Number Zero and Bitcoin</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/number-zero-and-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/number-zero-and-bitcoin/</guid><description>This essay by Robert Breedlove was published in his Medium blog.
Contribute.
Satoshi gave the world Bitcoin, a true “something for nothing.” His discovery of absolute scarcity for money is an unstoppable idea that is changing the world tremendously, just like its digital ancestor: the number zero.
Zero is Special # &amp;ldquo;In the history of culture the discovery of zero will always stand out as one of the greatest single achievements of the human race.</description></item><item><title>Dear Crypto &amp; Fiat Bros</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-bro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-bro/</guid><description>This article by Gigi was published on dergigi.com website.
Contribute.
An open letter to the confused and dismissive.
It should be obvious by now, but I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;ll have to spell it out anyway: Bitcoin, not blockchain. Bitcoin, not crypto. Bitcoin, not distributed ledger technology. Bitcoin, not DeFi. Bitcoin, not Web3. Bitcoin, not CBDCs. Bitcoin, not yield farming. Bitcoin, not centralized neo-banks that sell you fractional-reserve paper bitcoin. Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Fighting Fake Bitcoin</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/fighting-fake-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/fighting-fake-bitcoin/</guid><description>This article by Jameson Lopp was published in Casa blog.
Contribute.
Bitcoin provides strong assurances around the predictability and scarcity of its money supply. I wrote a detailed technical explanation of how it works here.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s controversial to state that this scarcity is one of bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s key properties and fundamental value drivers. If this property is violated, we have a big problem. So&amp;hellip;do we have a problem?</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin is The Mycelium of Money</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-is-the-mycelium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-is-the-mycelium/</guid><description>This article by Brandon Quittem was first published in his blog.
Contribute.
Foreward # I need to give credit to Dan Held for publishing his 4-part series comparing bitcoin’s origin to planting a tree. While I loved his series, I believe a more robust analogy is comparing bitcoin to fungi. If you’re new to this topic, strap in — it is my honor to initiate you into the fascinating world of fungi.</description></item><item><title>Доказательство жизни. Почему Биткоин — живой организм</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/pochemu-bitcoin-zhivoj-organizm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/pochemu-bitcoin-zhivoj-organizm/</guid><description>Перевод работы Gigi &amp;ldquo;Proof of Life. Why Bitcoin is a Living Organism&amp;rdquo; подготовлен дружественным проектом ∞/21M Определение жизни всегда было проблемой как для ученых, так и для философов. Хотя выдвинуто много определений, остается неясным, что именно отличает живое от неживого. Являются ли вирусы живыми? Молекулы ДНК? Компьютерные вирусы? Биологически продуцируемые минералы?
Ральф Меркл, изобретатель криптографического хеширования и дерева Меркла, выдвинул аргумент, что Биткоин является первым примером новой формы жизни. В настоящей серии статей я намерен серьезно отнестись к этому утверждению, изучить его подробно и посмотреть, что можно извлечь из рассмотрения Биткоина в качестве живого организма.</description></item><item><title>Самая мирная революция</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/samaya-mirnaya-revolyuciya/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/samaya-mirnaya-revolyuciya/</guid><description>Когда мы погружаемся в более деспотичный, авторитарный и хаотичный мир, вы можете однажды почувствовать утешение, зная, что самая высокая в мире система защиты материальных ценностей терпеливо ждет вас.
Перевод статьи Ника Картера от 7 Сентября 2019 г.
Особая благодарность @a48 за редактирование перевода
Поддержать проект
Люди не должны бояться своего правительства. Правительства должны бояться своего народа.
— V, V значит Вендетта
“Это покорность”, — пробормотал Редигер. “Шокирующая и простая идея, которая так и не была убедительно выражена, что вершина человеческого счастья находится в самом абсолютном подчинении”.</description></item><item><title>О Биткоин-вселенной</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/o-bitcoin-vselennoj/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/o-bitcoin-vselennoj/</guid><description>Мы, как Биткоин-амбассадоры должны говорить на общем языке и избегать эзотерики.
Поддержать проект “Я уверен, что мы, как Биткоин-амбассадоры должны говорить на общем языке и избегать эзотерики, чтобы наше послание могло с легкостью проникнуть в ум каждого. Я немного расскажу о Биткоин-вселенной и криптовалютынх активах, орудуя экзотерическими терминами. Ну что ж, начнем…”
Биткоин ~ интернет, альткоины ~ венчурные инвестиции # При взгляде на вселенную криптовалютынх активов, вырисовывается два основных полушария: 1) Биткоин и 2) все остальное, что обычно называют альтернативными криптоактивами, альткоинами или альтами.</description></item><item><title>Биткоин-диссиденты</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-dissidenty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-dissidenty/</guid><description>Неудержимый, цензуроустойчивый Биткоин завоевывает популярность среди протестующих и диссидентов по всему миру.
Поддержать проект &amp;ldquo;Можно сказать, что штаб-квартира Биткоина сейчас располагается в Лагосе. Или в Минске. Или в Гонконге&amp;rdquo;.
2020 год, прошедший под влиянием глобальной пандемией, политических и экономических кризисов во всем мире, заставил нас иначе взглянуть на многое. То, что раньше не привлекало особого внимания, начинает обретать значение. В криптовалюте также появляются новые мощные тенденции.
В то время как биткоин-трейдеры рассчитывают на новые денежные вливания от крупных инвесторов, во всем мире происходят изменения: Биткоин приходит к тем, кто в нем больше всего нуждается.</description></item><item><title>Биткоин = свобода</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-svoboda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-svoboda/</guid><description>Перевод статьи Росса Ульбрихта от 25 сентября 2019г. впервые опубликованной в блоге Росса на площадке Medium. Одна из нестареющих статей, опубликованных в мемпуле nakamotoinstitute.org.
Узнайте больше о Россе Ульбрихте на freeross.org. Вы можете подписать прошение о помиловании здесь.
Поддержать проект
Нечто особенное произошло примерно через год после того, как Сатоши подарил нам Биткоин. Что-то, чего никто не ожидал и многие считали невозможным. Попробуйте представить себе Биткоин тогда, до того, как вы могли что-то купить с его помощью, до того, как существовал обменный курс BTC/USD, до того, как хоть кто-то мог знать, приведет ли это к чему-то вообще.</description></item><item><title>Мифы о Биткоин-халвинге</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/mify-o-halvinge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/mify-o-halvinge/</guid><description>С халвингом связано множество заблуждений. Предлагаю подробнее рассмотреть некоторые из них.
Оригинал: Exploding Three Myths About the Upcoming Bitcoin Halving
Поддержать проект
Следующий Биткоин-халфинг (уполовинивание награды майнерам) уже на носу. В мае 2020 года вознаграждение за майнинг новых блоков будет сокращено вдвое с 12.5 до 6.25 биткоинов.
Халфинг — регулярное событие, которое случается каждые 210,000 блоков (примерно каждые четыре года). Это будет происходить до тех пор, пока, наконец, примерно в 2140 году не будет выпущен 21 миллион биткоинов.</description></item></channel></rss>