<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Bitcoin, Not Shitcoin</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/not-shitcoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/not-shitcoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why bitcoin is not only the best investment of our time, and the only good “crypto,” but the only moral, economic and philosophically sound place to store your wealth.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by Aleksandar Svetski was published in &lt;a href="https://bitcoinmagazine.com/culture/why-bitcoin-not-s-coin">Bitcoin Magazine&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>&lt;em>Hint: Beyond Bitcoin, it’s ALL shitcoin.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often get asked about “which crypto” is a good one to invest in. Of course, my answer is always bitcoin. Period.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article I’d like to lay out the rationale from three angles:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inalienable Property Rights</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/inalienable-property-rights/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/inalienable-property-rights/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This essay by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dergigi">Gigi&lt;/a> was published on &lt;a href="https://dergigi.com/2022/04/03/inalienable-property-rights">dergigi.com&lt;/a> website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;center>&lt;video src="https://21ideas.org/img/hayek.mp4" controls style="width: 100%">&lt;/video>&lt;/center>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Video bitcoinized by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RD_btc">RD ₿TC&lt;/a>, based on an edit by &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/9-uo-KfnkhI">Ampleforth&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Original source: &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/s-k_Fc63tZI">An interview with F.A. Hayek (1984)&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Law. Language. Money. The three paradigms of spontaneous and emergent order in society. Moral questions are at the root of it all:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Who should be allowed to speak?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Who should be allowed to publish?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Who should be allowed to have property?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Who should be allowed to defend said property?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Who should be allowed to issue and control the money?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It might not be obvious at first, but these questions and their respective areas - law, language, and money - are all related. They are related in general, but, more importantly, they are intimately related in the Gordian knot that is Bitcoin. Allow me, at least for a moment, to try to untangle this knot. Hopefully, without losing the thread that makes all of it hang together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Crypto Anarchist Manifesto</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-anarchist-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-anarchist-manifesto/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint info">
 &lt;p>From: &lt;a href="mailto:tcmay@netcom.com">tcmay@netcom.com&lt;/a> (Timothy C. May)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Subject: The Crypto Anarchist Manifesto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Date: Sun, 22 Nov 92 12:11:24 PST&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>Cypherpunks of the World,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several of you at the &amp;ldquo;physical Cypherpunks&amp;rdquo; gathering yesterday in Silicon Valley requested that more of the material passed out in meetings be available electronically to the entire readership of the Cypherpunks list, spooks, eavesdroppers, and all. &amp;lt;Gulp&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;Crypto Anarchist Manifesto&amp;rdquo; I read at the September 1992 founding meeting. It dates back to mid-1988 and was distributed to some like-minded techno-anarchists at the &amp;ldquo;Crypto &amp;lsquo;88&amp;rdquo; conference and then again at the &amp;ldquo;Hackers Conference&amp;rdquo; that year. I later gave talks at Hackers on this in 1989 and 1990.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Cypherpunk's Manifesto</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/cypherpunks-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 1993 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/cypherpunks-manifesto/</guid><description>&lt;p>by &lt;a href="ftp://soda.berkeley.edu/pub/cypherpunks/people/hughes.html">Eric Hughes&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Privacy is necessary for an open society in the electronic age. Privacy is not secrecy. A private matter is something one doesn&amp;rsquo;t want the whole world to know, but a secret matter is something one doesn&amp;rsquo;t want anybody to know. Privacy is the power to selectively reveal oneself to the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If two parties have some sort of dealings, then each has a memory of their interaction. Each party can speak about their own memory of this; how could anyone prevent it? One could pass laws against it, but the freedom of speech, even more than privacy, is fundamental to an open society; we seek not to restrict any speech at all. If many parties speak together in the same forum, each can speak to all the others and aggregate together knowledge about individuals and other parties. The power of electronic communications has enabled such group speech, and it will not go away merely because we might want it to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Bitcoin Like the Dutch Tulip Bubble?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/dutch-tulip-bubble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/dutch-tulip-bubble/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/skwp">Yan Pritzker&lt;/a> was published on &lt;a href="https://www.swanbitcoin.com/is-bitcoin-like-the-dutch-tulip-bubble">swanbitcoin.com&lt;/a> website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>If you could use tulips to instantly transmit value across the globe to anyone in any country, regard­less of whether they had a functioning govern­ment or banking system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the govern­ment couldn’t come to your door and take away your tulips or control who you could sell them to or in what ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If tulips could last for hundreds of years or millennia and be handed down to your children, redeemed for other forms of value.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everyone's a Scammer</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/everyones-a-scammer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/everyones-a-scammer/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bitstein">Michael Goldstein&lt;/a> was published on the &lt;a href="https://nakamotoinstitute.org/mempool/everyones-a-scammer/">Satoshi Nakamoto Institute&lt;/a> website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>


&lt;div class="youtubeWrapper">
 &lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fzw34HKjfjU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video" loading="lazy">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;div class="youtubeWrapper_hint">
 &lt;em>Suggested background reading music&lt;/em>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="theres-a-war-going-on">
 There&amp;rsquo;s a War Going On
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#theres-a-war-going-on">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bonnie and Clyde cannot simply rob First National Block Chain. They can hack servers and unencrypted wallet files or scan low-entropy brain wallets. But the costs of obtaining bitcoins hoarded on a high-entropy, password-protected paper wallet, for instance, are incredibly high. A computer cannot be expected to brute force the wallet in the universe’s lifetime, so a trespasser would have to employ expensive tactics such as kidnapping and torture on any prospective, individual target. Criminals, con artists, and swindlers cannot rely on violence to get the wealth they desire—it has become too cumbersome. These scoundrels must rely on good ol’ fashioned market forces.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Freedom of Value</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/freedom-of-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/freedom-of-value/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dergigi">Gigi&lt;/a> was published on &lt;a href="https://dergigi.com/2021/12/30/the-freedom-of-value">dergigi.com&lt;/a> website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;h2 id="how-value-for-value-fixes-the-monetization-of-information">
 How Value-for-Value Fixes the Monetization of Information
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#how-value-for-value-fixes-the-monetization-of-information">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The internet has a problem. Few people know that this problem exists, but hey, that&amp;rsquo;s the nature of serious, non-obvious problems: they are invisible until they aren&amp;rsquo;t. The problem with the internet is that information wants to be free. And if something wants to be free as in freedom, given enough time, it will also be free as in beer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Is The Only Real Meme</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-meme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-meme/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This thread by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dergigi">Gigi&lt;/a> was published in his &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dergigi/status/1425202084782264326">Twitter&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>“This is our meme world, everyone else is just living in it.” With this quote by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bitstein">@bitstein&lt;/a> I began my talk about “memes” and “the world” at the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BTCZitadelle">@BTCZitadelle&lt;/a> this weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="imageWrapper">
 &lt;img src="https://21ideas.org/img/meme-752-en.jpeg">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My talk wasn’t about memes, since I wouldn’t be able to top Bitstein’s talk anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was about the difference between memes and the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="imageWrapper">
 &lt;img src="https://21ideas.org/img/meme-723-en.jpeg">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Memes are thoughts, ideas, information.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“[A meme is] a unit of cultural information, such as a cultural practice or idea, that is transmitted verbally or by repeated action from one mind to another.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Number Zero and Bitcoin</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/number-zero-and-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/number-zero-and-bitcoin/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This essay by Robert Breedlove was published in his &lt;a href="https://breedlove22.medium.com/the-number-zero-and-bitcoin-4c193336db5b">Medium blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>Satoshi gave the world Bitcoin, a true “something for nothing.” His discovery of absolute scarcity for money is an unstoppable idea that is changing the world tremendously, just like its digital ancestor: the number zero.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="zero-is-special">
 Zero is Special
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#zero-is-special">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;In the history of culture the discovery of zero will always stand out as one of the greatest single achievements of the human race.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dear Crypto &amp; Fiat Bros</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-bro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/crypto-bro/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dergigi">Gigi&lt;/a> was published on &lt;a href="https://dergigi.com/2022/11/19/dear-crypto-fiat-bros">dergigi.com&lt;/a> website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>An open letter to the confused and dismissive.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It should be obvious by now, but I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;ll have to spell it out anyway: Bitcoin, not blockchain. Bitcoin, not crypto. Bitcoin, not distributed ledger technology. Bitcoin, not DeFi. Bitcoin, not Web3. Bitcoin, not CBDCs. Bitcoin, not yield farming. Bitcoin, not centralized neo-banks that sell you fractional-reserve paper bitcoin. Bitcoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think that Bitcoin is dead, you&amp;rsquo;ve been fooled by fiat journalists. If you think that Bitcoin is slow, or old tech, or MySpace, or the Model T, you&amp;rsquo;ve been fooled by snake-oil salesmen. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fighting Fake Bitcoin</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/fighting-fake-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/fighting-fake-bitcoin/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lopp">Jameson Lopp&lt;/a> was published in Casa &lt;a href="https://blog.keys.casa/securing-bitcoins-scarcity">blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>Bitcoin provides strong assurances around the predictability and scarcity of its money supply. I wrote a detailed technical explanation of how it works &lt;a href="https://blog.lopp.net/how-is-the-21-million-bitcoin-cap-defined-and-enforced">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s controversial to state that this scarcity is one of &lt;a href="https://nakamoto.com/what-are-the-key-properties-of-bitcoin/">bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s key properties&lt;/a> and fundamental value drivers. If this property is violated, we have a big problem. So&amp;hellip;do we have a problem?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">Bitcoin will not be a great store of value if most people are buying fake bitcoin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bitcoin is The Mycelium of Money</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-is-the-mycelium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-is-the-mycelium/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This series by Brandon Quittem was published in his &lt;a href="https://brandonquittem.com/bitcoin-is-the-mycelium-of-money">blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;h2 id="foreward">
 Foreward
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#foreward">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I need to give credit to Dan Held for publishing his 4-part series &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@danhedl/planting-bitcoin-sound-money-72e80e40ff62">comparing bitcoin’s origin to planting a tree&lt;/a>. While I loved his series, I believe a more robust analogy is comparing bitcoin to fungi. If you’re new to this topic, strap in — it is my honor to initiate you into the fascinating world of fungi.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Proof of Life. Why Bitcoin is a Living Organism</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/proof-of-life/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/proof-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dergigi">Gigi&lt;/a> was published on &lt;a href="https://dergigi.com/2019/08/07/proof-of-life">dergigi.com&lt;/a> website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>The definition of life has been a challenge for scientists and philosophers alike. While many definitions have been put forward, what precisely differentiates the living from the non-living remains elusive. Are viruses alive? DNA molecules? Computer viruses? Biologically produced minerals?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ralph Merkle, inventor of cryptographic hashing and namesake of the Merkle tree, made the argument that Bitcoin is the first example of a new form of life. In this article series, I intend to take this claim seriously, explore it further, and see what can be gleaned from viewing Bitcoin as a living organism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Most Peaceful Revolution</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/most-peaceful-revolution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/most-peaceful-revolution/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nic__carter">Nic Carter&lt;/a> was published in his &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@nic__carter/a-most-peaceful-revolution-8b63b64c203e">Medium blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People should not be afraid of their governments. Governments should be afraid of their people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>— V, V for Vendetta&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It’s submission,” Rediger murmured. “The shocking and simple idea, which had never been so forcefully expressed, that the summit of human happiness resides in the most absolute submission.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>— Michel Houellebecq, Soumission&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="make-no-mistake-bitcoiners-are-revolutionaries">
 Make no mistake, Bitcoiners are revolutionaries
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#make-no-mistake-bitcoiners-are-revolutionaries">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Libertarians had it all wrong. They sought to shrink the State’s influence by participating in the democratic process. This has been and remains a hopeless, Sisyphean task. Like Tolkien’s Ungoliant, the State hungers without limit, and its most engaged constituents duly reward it with votes for more growth, receiving in exchange ever-greater entitlements. Libertarians are, in a word, stuffed. Like the creeping gelatinous menace in The Blob, the State grows regardless of what you throw at it. Participating in democratic processes empowers it and entrenches the Orderly Civic Ritual as the only legitimate mode of political engagement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Universe</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-universe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-universe/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This thread by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Breedlove22">Robert Breedlove&lt;/a> was published in his &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Breedlove22/status/1141567060847149056">Twitter&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>As ambassadors of Bitcoin, I believe we must speak the common tongue and avoid esoteric language so that our message can penetrate minds far and wide. Here, I will shed some light on the Bitcoin and cryptoasset universe in an exoteric nutshell. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we look at the cryptoasset universe, there are two distinct hemispheres: 1) Bitcoin and 2) everything else, which are commonly known as Alternative Cryptoassets or Alts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Dissidents</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-dissidents/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-dissidents/</guid><description>&lt;p>The global pandemic and interwoven political and economic crises became fertile ground for Bitcoin to become a tool for human rights.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by Anna Baydakova was published on &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2020/12/08/bitcoin-dissidents-those-who-need-it-most/">CoinDesk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>“You can say that Bitcoin’s headquarters is in Lagos now. Or in Minsk. Or Hong Kong.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The year 2020, shaped by the global pandemic and political and economic crises worldwide, made us reconsider many things. Stuff that didn’t catch much attention before starts to matter. In crypto, new, powerful trends are also on the rise.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Equals Freedom</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-equals-freedom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoin-equals-freedom/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This essay by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RealRossU">Ross Ulbricht&lt;/a> was first published in his &lt;a href="https://rossulbricht.medium.com/bitcoin-equals-freedom-6c33986b4852">Medium blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read more about Ross Ulbricht on &lt;a href="https://freeross.org/">freeross.org&lt;/a>. You can sign a petition for clemency &lt;a href="https://freeross.org/petition">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>Something special happened in the first year or so after Satoshi gave us Bitcoin, something no one expected and many thought was impossible. Try to imagine Bitcoin back then, before you could buy things with it, before there was an exchange rate, before anyone really knew what, if anything, would happen with it. Bitcoin didn’t start out as money. It became money, but it did so unlike any money that came before it. For all the things Bitcoin has made possible, for all the ways it is changing our world, we don’t fully appreciate or even understand what happened in those early days, when it was just a plaything for geeks.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>