<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>protocol on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/tags/protocol/</link><description>Recent content in protocol on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/tags/protocol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Who Controls Bitcoin Core?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/who-controls-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/who-controls-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>Understanding how the focal point of Bitcoin development operates.
This article by Jameson Lopp was published in his blog.
Contribute.
if you&amp;rsquo;d prefer to consume this essay in audio format, you can listen to it here (narrated by Guy Swann of the Bitcoin Audible Podcast.) The question of who controls the ability to merge code changes into Bitcoin Core’s GitHub repository tends to come up on a recurring basis. This has been cited as a “central point of control” of the Bitcoin protocol by various parties over the years, but I argue that the question itself is a red herring that stems from an authoritarian perspective — this model does not apply to Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin's Eternal Struggle</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoins-eternal-struggle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/bitcoins-eternal-struggle/</guid><description>How Bitcoin Thrives on the Edge between Order and Chaos
This article by Gigi was published on dergigi.com website.
Contribute.
if you&amp;rsquo;d prefer to consume this essay in audio format, you can listen to it here (narrated by Guy Swann of the Bitcoin Audible Podcast.) Bitcoin works. No matter what other opinions you hold about this strange phenomenon, it undoubtedly works, marches on, or, as I (and others) have previously argued, is alive.</description></item><item><title>On Bitcoin’s UX</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/on-bitcoins-ux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/on-bitcoins-ux/</guid><description>This article by Gigi was published on swanbitcoin.com website.
Contribute.
Why the internet doesn’t feel as clumsy anymore is twofold: (1) we got used to the novel concepts the internet brought with it, and (2) countless layers of abstraction make interacting with the base layer easier.
There is an ongoing discus­sion in the Bitcoin space revolving around the topic of user experi­ence, or UX for short. Bitcoin still feels weird, clunky, and compli­cated at times.</description></item></channel></rss>