<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hodl on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/practice/hodl/</link><description>Recent content in Hodl on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/practice/hodl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Electrum Bitcoin Wallet</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/electrum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/electrum/</guid><description>This guide by Arman The Parman was published in his blog.
Contribute.
Why Electrum? # This is a detailed guide on how to use the Electrum Bitcoin Wallet, with solutions to all its traps and quirks -something I’ve developed after several years of use, and teaching students about Bitcoin security/privacy. Electrum is not the best Bitcoin wallet for the person who wants to keep everything as simple as possible, and preferring to remain at the beginner level.</description></item><item><title>Installing Blue Wallet</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/blue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/blue/</guid><description>This guide by @econoalchemist was published in Bitcoin Magazine.
Contribute.
If you have an iPhone and have bitcoin, then I highly recommend using Blue Wallet to secure your BTC. This article will walk you through the basic steps for installing, securing and using Blue Wallet on iPhone. But, before getting started, it is a good idea to have a pen and paper ready. Remember to start with small amounts of bitcoin until these concepts make more sense and you are comfortable putting your funds in a mobile wallet.</description></item><item><title>SeedSigner: DIY Bitcoin Signing Device</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/seedsigner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/seedsigner/</guid><description>This comprehensive how-to guide walks you through unboxing, setting up and signing bitcoin transactions with the air-gapped SeedSigner device.
This guide by @econoalchemist was published in Bitcoin Magazine.
Contribute.
This guide demonstrates how to self-custody bitcoin using the SeedSigner. SeedSigner is a project that brings together free and open-source code, inexpensive and general-purpose hardware, and a do-it-yourself (DIY) approach to taking personal responsibility of your bitcoin.
Source
Unboxing # This section demonstrates what is included in the full SeedSigner kit.</description></item><item><title>What is Coldcard?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/coldcard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/coldcard/</guid><description>This guide by Bitcoin Q+A was published on bitcoiner.guide website.
Contribute.
What is Coldcard? # Coldcard is a hardware wallet designed by the Coinkite team. A hardware wallets is a device with one main purpose, to keep your bitcoin private keys safe and secure. Anyone with access to your private keys has access to all of the bitcoin in that wallet. Coldcard does not come with its own app or any additional software.</description></item></channel></rss>