<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>private keys on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/tags/private-keys/</link><description>Recent content in private keys on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/tags/private-keys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Phoenix: The Non-Custodial Lightning Wallet</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/phoenix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/phoenix/</guid><description>How to use the Lightning Network without trusting anyone? Take Back Control of Your Sats in the Lightning Network.
The guide written by Tony⚡️.
Contribute.
Intro # Now I would like to provide you a guide on Phoenix — the non-custodial Lightning wallet. This guide will be useful for those who already familiar with the Lightning Network and have evaluated the interaction with it in practice. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;ve already been using a custodial wallet like Wallet Of Satoshi and you want to gain more control over your funds, hold your sats independently in Lightning Network, and minimize the level of trust to a third party.</description></item><item><title>Electrum Bitcoin Wallet</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/electrum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/electrum/</guid><description>This guide by Arman The Parman was published in his blog.
Contribute.
Why Electrum? # This is a detailed guide on how to use the Electrum Bitcoin Wallet, with solutions to all its traps and quirks -something I’ve developed after several years of use, and teaching students about Bitcoin security/privacy. Electrum is not the best Bitcoin wallet for the person who wants to keep everything as simple as possible, and preferring to remain at the beginner level.</description></item><item><title>Installing Blue Wallet</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/blue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/blue/</guid><description>This guide by @econoalchemist was published in Bitcoin Magazine.
Contribute.
If you have an iPhone and have bitcoin, then I highly recommend using Blue Wallet to secure your BTC. This article will walk you through the basic steps for installing, securing and using Blue Wallet on iPhone. But, before getting started, it is a good idea to have a pen and paper ready. Remember to start with small amounts of bitcoin until these concepts make more sense and you are comfortable putting your funds in a mobile wallet.</description></item><item><title>SeedSigner: DIY Bitcoin Signing Device</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/seedsigner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/seedsigner/</guid><description>This comprehensive how-to guide walks you through unboxing, setting up and signing bitcoin transactions with the air-gapped SeedSigner device.
This guide by @econoalchemist was published in Bitcoin Magazine.
Contribute.
This guide demonstrates how to self-custody bitcoin using the SeedSigner. SeedSigner is a project that brings together free and open-source code, inexpensive and general-purpose hardware, and a do-it-yourself (DIY) approach to taking personal responsibility of your bitcoin.
Source
Unboxing # This section demonstrates what is included in the full SeedSigner kit.</description></item></channel></rss>