<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Wallets: How, Why and When to Hold Your Own Private Keys</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/how-to-hold-private-keys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/how-to-hold-private-keys/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not Your Keys, Not Your Bitcoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by Brandon Quittem was published on &lt;a href="https://www.swanbitcoin.com/bitcoin-wallets-not-your-keys-not-your-bitcoin/">swanbitcoin.com&lt;/a> website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>Alright so you’ve acquired some Bitcoin, now what’s the best way to store it? Here we’ll take you through the process of finding the right Bitcoin wallet for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although it seems like a straight­for­ward question, there is a surprising amount of nuance to consider. &lt;em>How much Bitcoin do you have? How often do you plan to spend it? Are you confi­dent your keys are more secure with you than with a regulated custo­di­an’s cold storage?&lt;/em> Answering these questions will help deter­mine the right solution for you. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a bitcoin seed phrase and how does it work?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/seed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/seed/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by Stephen Hall was published in &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/blog/what-is-a-bitcoin-seed-phrase">Unchained blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>As we regularly cover in our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0yflwOcix9c&amp;amp;list=PLUM8mrUjWoPTo2TCYb_67qOwxP_EVbGiL">Continuing Education webinars&lt;/a>, there are several key terms to know about as a bitcoin user. When it comes to protecting your bitcoin, few are as important as &lt;strong>seed phrase&lt;/strong>. Your seed phrase is where everything is derived from: these 12 or 24 words generate the keys that allow you to spend your funds, making it critically important that you protect this information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate guide to storing your bitcoin seed phrase backups</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/seed-security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/seed-security/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by Stephen Hall was published in &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/blog/how-to-store-bitcoin-seed-phrase-backups/">Unchained blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>In bitcoin, it’s always important to secure your seeds, but how exactly do you do that? In previous articles, we’ve discussed &lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/en/seed">what seed phrases are and how they work&lt;/a>, and some of the &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/blog/seed-phrase-backup-methods-recording-paper-metal/">most common methods for recording them on various mediums&lt;/a>. In this article, we cover how and where to store your seed phrase backups in different bitcoin custody contexts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is your passphrase strong enough?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/passphrase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/passphrase/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by SatoshiLabs was published in &lt;a href="https://blog.trezor.io/is-your-passphrase-strong-enough-d687f44c63af">Trezor blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>There are various approaches to creating a good &lt;a href="https://blog.trezor.io/passphrase-the-ultimate-protection-for-your-accounts-3a311990925b">passphrase for your wallet&lt;/a>. You can go with something that is quick to type but not so easy to remember, such as “5Xai1WhSYu”, or you can opt for a sentence that is easy to remember but takes longer to enter into your Trezor, such as “Buying a Trezor was the wisest choice I ever made.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is multisig?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/what-is-multisig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/what-is-multisig/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why multisig is the best approach for long-term cold storage for most people, and how to make the most of it for your generational wealth.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by Tom Honzik and Stephen Hall was published in &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/features/what-is-multisig">Unchained blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>When it comes to storing your bitcoin, multisignature — or multisig for short — is widely recognized as one of the most secure methods. It can eliminate risks associated with exchanges and custodians, and simultaneously addresses the most common issues with self-custody. In this article, we’re going to walk through why you should hold your own bitcoin keys, what standard singlesignature self-custody looks like, and how multisig is an improvement for long-term cold storage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The best Bitcoin hardware wallets</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/hwws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/hwws/</guid><description>&lt;p>An overview of the most popular devices, including Trezor, Ledger, Coldcard, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article by Anil was published in &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/blog/best-bitcoin-hardware-wallets">Unchained blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>As the events of 2022 have illustrated, nothing is more important than taking self-custody of your bitcoin and removing counterparty risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>“Your keys, your bitcoin. Not your keys, not your bitcoin.”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>— Andreas Antonopoulos&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When you entrust your bitcoin to a third party (e.g., an exchange), you are at their mercy when it comes to accessing your wealth. This can entail many risks and inconveniences, from unplanned outages and scheduled maintenance to account closures. The most painful possible outcome by far is a complete loss of your bitcoin in the event of a bankruptcy or hack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multisig Part I: Why Multisig?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/multisig-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/multisig-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the first of a series of articles that will describe the details of how multisignature functions with bitcoin. We’ve written extensively about &lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/gradually-then-suddenly">bitcoin economics&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/blog/category/data-science/">data science&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/blog/category/bitcoin-astronomy/">astronomy&lt;/a>, and we feel that it is the right time to explore the deeper technical details of multisignature to help users protect their bitcoin as we approach the 3rd halvening era. We expect that bitcoin will become much more valuable in the future, and friends should always help friends better secure bitcoin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multisig Part II: Single Keys are the Foundation of Multisignature</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/multisig-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/multisig-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the second article in our series on multisignature. Read part one here: &lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/en/multisig-1">Why Multisig?&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="book-hint btc">
 &lt;p>This article was published in &lt;a href="https://unchained.com/blog/single-signature-wallet">Unchained blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://21ideas.org/contribute/">Contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;/blockquote>

&lt;p>Before diving into technical details about how multisignature addresses and wallets function, it’s important to have a baseline understanding of how single signature wallets, the most common form of bitcoin wallet, function behind the scenes. Most of the general technical details that apply to single signature wallets apply to multisignature wallets, but single signature wallets tend to combine multiple steps and functions, whereas multisignature generally separates steps. First, let’s unpack the word “wallet” in the context of bitcoin.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>