<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scalability on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/tags/scalability/</link><description>Recent content in scalability on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/tags/scalability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Part I</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/1/</guid><description>Contents ... Part I
Part II
Part III
This essay by Dhruv Bansal was published in Unchained blog.
Contribute.
The desire to travel far away and start a new currency will become a powerful driver of human expansion into space.
Earth will run on bitcoin, but colonies on Mars, the outer planets, and distant stars will not. Though faraway colonies will value and trade bitcoin, they will choose to launch, defend and use their own local blockchains.</description></item><item><title>Part II</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/2/</guid><description>Contents ... Part I
Part II
Part III
This essay by Dhruv Bansal was published in Unchained blog.
Contribute.
This is Part II in a series of speculations about the hyperbitcoinized future. In Part I, we defined the First Law of Bitcoin Astronomy and described how it incentivizes searching for energy to power our growing civilization.
In this part, we continue to follow the energy and speculate about how money and society coevolve as humanity expands through space.</description></item><item><title>Part III</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/3/</guid><description>Contents ... Part I
Part II
Part III
This essay by Dhruv Bansal was published in Unchained blog.
Contribute.
This is Part III in a series of speculations about the hyperbitcoinized future. In Part I, we defined the First Law of Bitcoin Astronomy and described how it leads to new blockchains as humanity expands through the solar system. In Part II, we described a Second Law which leads to nested blockchains the size of solar systems and beyond, hashing vast energies on cosmic timescales.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin is Not Too Slow</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/gradually-then-suddenly/bitcoin-is-not-too-slow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/gradually-then-suddenly/bitcoin-is-not-too-slow/</guid><description>Contents ... Gradually, Then Suddenly: Intro Bitcoin Can’t Be Copied Bitcoin Is Not Too Volatile Bitcoin Does Not Waste Energy Bitcoin is Not Too Slow Bitcoin Fixes This Bitcoin, Not Blockchain Bitcoin is Not Backed by Nothing Bitcoin is Not a Pyramid Scheme Bitcoin Cannot be Banned Bitcoin is Not for Criminals Bitcoin Obsoletes All Other Money Bitcoin is a Rally Cry Bitcoin is Common Sense Bitcoin is Antifragile Bitcoin is One for All Bitcoin is the Great Definancialization This article by Parker Lewis was first published in Unchained blog.</description></item></channel></rss>