<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lightning on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/tags/lightning/</link><description>Recent content in lightning on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/tags/lightning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Phoenix: The Non-Custodial Lightning Wallet</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/phoenix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/phoenix/</guid><description>How to use the Lightning Network without trusting anyone? Take Back Control of Your Sats in the Lightning Network.
The guide written by Tony⚡️.
Contribute.
Intro # I would like to share a guide on Phoenix — the non-custodial Lightning wallet. This guide will be useful for those who already are familiar with the Lightning Network and have some experience using it. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;ve already been using a custodial wallet like Wallet Of Satoshi and you want to gain more control over your funds, hold your sats in Lightning Network, and minimize the level of trust to a third party.</description></item><item><title>What is Lightning Network?</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/what-is-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/what-is-lightning-network/</guid><description>Why should you care about Lightning Network, how does it work and how to use it? We&amp;rsquo;ll answer these and many other questions in this guide.
The article written by Tony⚡️.
Contribute.
Lightning Network is a decentralized system for instant micro payments. Bitcoin, the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely used and valued cryptocurrency, allows anyone to transfer value without the need for a trusted third party. Bitcoin supports an advanced scripting system that allows users to program instructions for managing their funds.</description></item><item><title>Part I</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/1/</guid><description>Contents ... Part I
Part II
Part III
This essay by Dhruv Bansal was published in Unchained blog.
Contribute.
The desire to travel far away and start a new currency will become a powerful driver of human expansion into space.
Earth will run on bitcoin, but colonies on Mars, the outer planets, and distant stars will not. Though faraway colonies will value and trade bitcoin, they will choose to launch, defend and use their own local blockchains.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Wallets</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-wallets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/lightning-wallets/</guid><description>With repeated bumps of the popularity of monkey pictures in the Bitcoin blockchain and in anticipation of the upcoming bull market, fees in the mainnet don&amp;rsquo;t make anyone happy.
Fees in the network can reach hundreds of sats per virtual byte, and this is far from the limit. Source.
Lightning Network provides a solution to the painful problem of high fees, but you need to act thoughtfully, without hurrying. That&amp;rsquo;s why today I propose to analyze the best available Lightning wallets, evaluate the pros and cons of each of them, so that you can choose the best solution and finally forget (or at least minimize the stress) about high fees.</description></item><item><title>LNbits: A Swiss knife among Lightning apps</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/lnbits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/lnbits/</guid><description>LNbits is the Swiss knife among lightning apps – invoices, tips, paywalls, onchain wallet monitoring, event ticketing and more.
The guide written by Tony⚡️.
Contribute.
LNbits # Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to take a look at a wallet app accessible right from the browser that boasts so many features that it&amp;rsquo;s the envy of any software. This is LNbits.
It is worth starting with the fact that this service is still in the phase of active development, and some functionality is yet to be implemented.</description></item><item><title>How Lightning Address Works</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/how-lightning-address-works/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/how-lightning-address-works/</guid><description>More experienced users know, that nowadays you can send satoshis directly to Lightning Address in user@domain format. But how exactly does this work?
In this short article I would like to explain it to those who do not know it. At the same time, I will describe the basics of Lightning invoices and LNURL-pay protocol.
This article by @heisenberg was published on stacker.news website.
Contribute.
Lightning invoices basics # Lightning Invoices are nowadays the standard for sending and receiving funds on the Lightning Network.</description></item><item><title>Part II</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/2/</guid><description>Contents ... Part I
Part II
Part III
This essay by Dhruv Bansal was published in Unchained blog.
Contribute.
This is Part II in a series of speculations about the hyperbitcoinized future. In Part I, we defined the First Law of Bitcoin Astronomy and described how it incentivizes searching for energy to power our growing civilization.
In this part, we continue to follow the energy and speculate about how money and society coevolve as humanity expands through space.</description></item><item><title>Part III</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/ba/3/</guid><description>Contents ... Part I
Part II
Part III
This essay by Dhruv Bansal was published in Unchained blog.
Contribute.
This is Part III in a series of speculations about the hyperbitcoinized future. In Part I, we defined the First Law of Bitcoin Astronomy and described how it leads to new blockchains as humanity expands through the solar system. In Part II, we described a Second Law which leads to nested blockchains the size of solar systems and beyond, hashing vast energies on cosmic timescales.</description></item></channel></rss>