<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interact on 21ideas</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/practice/interact/</link><description>Recent content in Interact on 21ideas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://21ideas.org/en/practice/interact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Каждому следует запустить собственную Биткоин-ноду!</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/practice/bitcoin-noda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/practice/bitcoin-noda/</guid><description>Предлагаю начать с того, что такое биткоин-нода и после перейти к причинам, по которым стоит запустить собственную ноду.
Что такое биткоин-нода? # Биткоин – это одноранговая цифровая наличность, которая регулируется сетью узлов (нод). Нода – это просто компьютер, на котором установлено программное обеспечение Биткоин. Биткоин-ноды – это компьютеры со специально установленным программным обеспечением, которые обмениваются транзакциями с другими узлами сети и проверяют их действительность. Пользователи Биткоин-нод сотрудничают с Биткоин-майнерами для поддержания целостности системы.</description></item><item><title>Orangepilling in 5 min</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/orangepilling-in-5-min/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/orangepilling-in-5-min/</guid><description>This thread was published by Hector Alvero in Twitter.
Contribute.
What do you do when you meet someone casually at a party or social event and they ask you the tiny question with the huge answer:
What is Bitcoin?
We know the best way to orange pill someone is by asking questions to plant seeds that nurture curiosity. That works great with people we know or see often, but what about strangers you’ve just met and may never see again?</description></item><item><title>5 tips for teaching Bitcoin</title><link>https://21ideas.org/en/5-tips-for-teaching-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://21ideas.org/en/5-tips-for-teaching-bitcoin/</guid><description>This article by John Tinkelenberg was published in Casa blog.
Contribute.
It’s easy to adopt bitcoin as an individual, but sharing your knowledge with others — or orange-pilling as we say in the industry — can be hard. Bitcoin is often a tricky subject to discuss with friends and relatives in addition to being a completely different asset to own and manage.
Now that bitcoin is mainstream, most of us are exploring bitcoin for the first time.</description></item></channel></rss>